贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
是我
Yeah.
我是约翰·拉格兰
This is John Raglan.
我是12年前你妈妈那起谋杀案的
Uh... I was the lead investigator
案件调查负责人
on your mother's homicide 12 years ago.
我记得你  拉格兰探长
I remember you, Detective Raglan.
听着  我...
Listen, I...
我们得谈谈你母亲的案子
We need to talk about your mother's case.
有些事情你还不知道
There's something you don't know.
在第4街和主街交口有个咖啡馆
There's a coffee shop at 4th and main.
一小时后在那跟我碰头
Meet me there in an hour.
一个人来  别带其他警察
Just you. No cops.
-贝克特  -嘿
- Beckett. - Hey.
进来
Come on in.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk for a second?
那就是他
That's him.
女士  我说"别带其他警察"你没听懂吗
Lady, what part of "No cops" didn't you understand?
-他不是警察  -那他是哪根葱
- He's not a cop. - Well, who the hell is he, then?
我很信任的一个人
He's someone I trust.
加咖啡吗
More coffee?
谢谢
Thank you.
说说我母亲的谋杀案还有什么我不知道
Tell me what I don't know about my mom's murder.
现在大家喝咖啡
Everybody drinks their coffee
都用那些硬纸壳
outta cardboard cups these days
或是那些塑料旅行杯
or those plastic travel mugs.
但是
But there's...
但是陶瓷有一种特别的感觉
There's something about the way
能温暖你的手
ceramic warms your hands that...
那感觉很奇怪
It's weird...
你注意到的事情
The things you notice.
我刚从医生那儿听到了一个坏消息
I just got the long face from the doc.
淋巴瘤
Lymphoma.
还有六个月
Six months.
很抱歉
Sorry to hear about that.
每年过节的时候
Every year around the holidays,
他们都在电视上播放《圣诞颂歌》
they--they run that "Christmas Carol" on local tv.
当我还是孩子的时候
When was a kid,
我记得雅各布·马利把我吓得要死[电影主角]
I remember, Jacob Marley scared the hell out of me,
被逼着拖着那条锁链进入另一个世界
forced to drag that--that chain around in the next world.
"我戴着那条我制造的锁链"
"I wear the chain I forged in life."
"我一环一环把它做好"
"I made it link by link."
我在警徽背后隐藏了很多罪恶
I hid a lot of sins behind my badge.
现在那罪恶成了我的锁链
And now I gotta carry 'em.
但是你妈妈的案子
But your mother's case...
压得我喘不过气来
that one weighs a ton.
为什么  因为你明知有蹊跷
Why? Because you wrote it off
却把那个案子算作是帮派暴力案件吗
as random gang violence when you knew it wasn't?
-我是服从命令  -是啊
- I did what I was told. - Yeah.
之后我一字不提是因为我害怕了
And I kept quiet because I was afraid.
一年前
About a year ago,
在你的分局有过一次人质挟持事件
there was a hostage standoff in your precinct.
你击杀了一个名叫迪克·库南的杀手
You killed a hit man named Dick Coonan.
当时报纸上大篇幅报道
It was a big deal in the papers.
大家都知道了
People noticed.
谁雇佣了库南杀害我妈妈
Who hired Coonan to kill my mom?
你需要知道前因后果
You need some context here.
事情始于19年前
This thing started about 19 years ago,
那时候我还不知道乔安·贝克特是谁
back before I ever knew who Johanna Beckett was.
19年前  我...
19 years ago, I...
我犯了一个大错
I made a bad mistake.
之后就如多尼诺骨牌一般  一错再错
And that started the dominoes falling.
其中一个就是你妈妈...
And one of 'em was your mom--
所有人卧倒  快
Everybody, on the ground. Now!
离窗户远一点  远离窗户
Back away from the window! Away from the window!
-你被打中了  -我没事  不是我的血
- You're hit. - I'm fine. It's not my blood.
1L40  第4街和主街交口发生枪击
1 lincoln 40, I have shots fired on 4th and main.
我需要后援和救护车
I need backup and an ambulance.
1L40  请重复  请重复
1 lincoln 40, repeat your last transmission.
-没有收到  1L40  请重复  -卡塞尔
- You were broken. 1 lincoln 40, repeat. - Castle?
1L40  请重复
Dispatch to 1 lincoln 40, repeat.
1L40  1L40  你还在吗
Dispatch to 1 lincoln 40. 1 lincoln 40, are you there?
1L40
1 lincoln 40...
请注意  这是一起谋杀案
Please be advised, this is now a homicide.
翻译：大卫熊  末末  咖啡十三  小易  千花  小蛮腰
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳  千花   后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
退休的纽约警察
Retired NYPD cop gunned down
在我的人面前被射杀
in front of one of my people,
这意味着新闻发布会
which means I'm gonna have to do
又会很麻烦
a damn press conference.
告诉我你来这儿  不会是没带后援吧
Tell me you didn't come down here without backup.
-长官  -我们是她的后援  队长
- Sir, I-- - We were backing her, captain.
是啊  我们就在巷子后面
Yeah, we were just, uh, down the block.
是啊
Yeah. Uh-huh.
我该拿你怎么办
What the hell am I gonna do with you?
你得让我调查这个案子
You're gonna let me work this case.
你过于情绪化  脸上都看得出
You're too close to it. It's all over your face.
你在想  拉格兰
You're thinking, what was
死前到底想告诉你什么
Raglan gonna tell me before he died,
而你应该想的事情是
when you should be thinking
你应该怎么抓到杀死他的人
how you're gonna catch the guy that killed him.
长官  拉格兰是因为要告诉我一些
Sir, Raglan was killed because he was gonna
我妈妈案子的事情才被杀的
tell me something about my mother's case.
没人比我更了解那个案子
Nobody knows it better than I do.
是啊  但是我了解你
Yeah, but I know you.
你会不顾一切
You're gonna want to pick up those scissors
拼命追查这个案子
and run around the house with 'em,
但是我告诉你  放慢脚步
But I'm telling you now, walk, don't run.
跟着证据顺藤摸瓜  而不是反过来
Go where the evidence leads, not the other way around.
你听懂了吗
Do you read me?
是的  长官  铭记于心
Yes, sir. Loud and clear.
发现一颗子弹嵌在隔间里
Found a bullet embedded in the booth.
点338马格姆手枪  很奇特的凶器
.338 magnum. Fairly exotic antipersonnel round.
能还原弹道轨迹吗
Can you show me the trajectory?
可以  就在这儿
Yeah, it's right over here.
好的  射击点来自对面大楼的四楼
All right, I make the building across the street, fourth floor.
-埃斯波西托  -好的  我去封锁大楼
- Esposito. - Yeah, I'll lock it down.
肯定有人会看到一些情况
Somebody had to have seen something in there.
莱恩  我敢肯定杀拉格兰的杀手
Ryan, I am betting that Raglan's murderer
跟踪他来到这里
followed him here.
你能不能去询问他的邻居
Can you check with his neighbors,
看看有没有人今早在他家附近逗留
See if anyone was hanging around his place this morning?
-没问题  -谢谢
- You got it. - Thanks.
嘿
Hey.
-嘿  -你还好吗
- Hey. - You good?
是啊  应该是把血迹洗掉了
Yeah. I think I got it all off my hands.
命案就发生在眼前跟其他事情是不一样的
It's different when it happens right in front of you.
你会清楚地看到人呼出最后一口气
You're close enough to watch the lights go out.
是啊
Yeah.
当我看到你衣服上的血迹
When I saw the blood on your shirt,
我还以为你中弹了
I thought you'd been shot.
我要去12分局
Um, I'm gonna go to the 12th.
我把你送到你家吧
How about I drop you off at your place?
想都别想
Not a chance.
好吧
Okay.
我检查了四楼
So I checked out the fourth floor.
没有指纹  没有弹匣  也没有目击者
There's no prints, no casings, no witnesses,
但好消息是  那幢大楼有安保监控
But the good news is, it's a secure building.
只能通过大厅进出
The only way in or out is through the lobby,
而想要通过大厅的十字旋转门
and nobody gets through the lobby turnstiles
必须有门卡
without a key card.
就是说枪手有门卡
So our shooter had a card.
没错  他们正把员工名单发过来
Yeah, they're sending over a list of all their employees.
另外还有
They're also downloading
大厅的监控录像
surveillance video from the lobby.
各位  我跟他邻居谈了谈
Hey. So I, uh, talked to the neighbors.
拉格兰是鳏夫  没能找到近亲
Raglan was a widower. No next of kin that I could find.
管理员说基本没人找他
Super said he didn't really even have visitors,
只有一个伙计偶尔过来
except every once in a while, his buddy would come over
看洋基队比赛
to watch a yankee game.
叫盖瑞·麦卡利斯特  是拉格兰的老同学
Gary McCallister, Raglan's old academy classmate.
联系麦卡利斯特
Get ahold of McCallister.
看他能否过来趟  我得跟他谈谈
See if he'll come. I want to talk to him.
好的
You got it.
十九年前
19 years ago.
-什么  -拉格兰想跟我们说
- What's that? - Raglan started telling us about something
发生在十九年前的某件事
that happened 19 years ago.
我母亲被害于十二年前
My mom's murder was 12 years ago.
说不通啊
It's not making any sense.
知道吗  我鼎盛的年华
you know, I sacrificed my best years
还有噩梦般的婚姻都献给了这鬼城市
and worst marriages to this damn city.
本以为已经够糟了  原来还有更糟的
You'd think that'd be enough, but it never is.
连我的好朋友都不放过
Had to gobble up my best friend, too.
你最后一次见约翰·拉格兰是什么时候
When was the last time you saw John Raglan?
大约一周前  他跟我说他快死了
Week ago. Told me he was dying.
他还说什么了
What else did he tell you?
这还不够吗
Isn't that enough?
不过我不大明白
But I don't get it.
拉格兰在你当警察前就退休了
Raglan was retired by the time you come on the job.
怎么会跟你有瓜葛
What'd he want with you?
拉格兰正在协助我
Raglan was helping me with a-a cold case
调查一宗悬案
that I was working on.
我认为他应该就是被人灭口了
I believe he was killed to keep him quiet.
拉格兰似乎认为这宗悬案
Look, Raglan seemed to think that the case
跟他十九年前做过的某件事有关
had something to do with something he did 19 years ago.
你知道是什么事吗
What was he into back then?
什么事
What was he into?
约翰·拉格兰又不是圣人
John Raglan was no angel,
当时的纽约也和现在大不一样
and New York was a different city back then,
我只能告诉你
And I'm here to tell you,
小屁孩过家家式的调查一点用没有
Kid gloves didn't get it done out there.
什么事情都需要警察插一脚
You police a damn theme park.
你要是现在想给什么人沉冤昭雪啥的
You're lookin' to start some half-assed truth commission.
我可没那闲工夫
You can count me out.
我并不是想否定拉格兰的过去
I'm not trying to tarnish Raglan's memory.
我只想找到杀他的凶手
I'm trying to find his murderer.
我说过让他离那个人远点儿
I told him not to get involved with that guy.
-谁  -瓦肯·西蒙斯
- With who? - Vulcan Simmons.
瓦肯·西蒙斯是谁
Vulcan Simmons?
他操纵着纽约大半的毒品交易
He runs half the drug trade in New York.
拉格兰常嫖娼[PONY:Prostitute of New York]
Raglan liked to play the ponies.
差不多十九年前
19, 20 years ago would be about the time
他正走背字
he had a string of bad luck
手头很紧
and he was hard up for money.
然后突然宽裕了
And then he wasn't.
有传言说
Word was, he got well
他帮西蒙斯运毒
working as a dope courier for Simmons,
开着巡逻车  辗转于各镇之间
moving product across town in his patrol car.
拉格兰在凶案组干了四年
Raglan worked homicide for four years.
我很清楚西蒙斯会斩尽杀绝
And I know Simmons put people in the ground.
要是是我的案子
If it were my case,
我就好好研究瓦肯·西蒙斯
I'd take a hard look at Vulcan Simmons.
暴力攻击  蓄意谋杀  敲诈勒索
Assault, attempted murder, extortion,
恶意强占  威胁目击证人...
possession with intent, witness intimidation...
然后就不了了之
Then it looks like it just dries up.
多年来  在没人逮捕过他
Nobody's booked him in years.
这说明什么  他皈依我佛了
So what does that mean, he found religion?
说明他学聪明了  更善于掩藏自己
It means he got smart. Swimminng deeper waters.
看来华盛顿高地事件后他进步不小
Guess he's come a long way since Washington Heights.
等等  什么  华盛顿高地
Wait. What? You said Washington Heights?
过去有段时间
Back in the day,
西蒙斯曾在华盛顿高地
Simmons used to run the drug trade
搞毒品交易
in Washington Heights.
我妈妈和她的同事们
My mom and a group of her colleagues,
发动了一场叫做
they put together this campaign
"还我家园"的活动
called "Take back the Neighborhood".
他们试图借此将毒贩
They were trying to get drug dealers off the streets
赶出华盛顿高地
in Washington Heights.
由于西蒙斯正是那个地区的老大
With Simmons running all the dope in that neighborhood,
那场活动应该让他损失不小
that campaign would cost him.
而那个职业杀手库南又是个瘾君子
That hit man, Coonan, we know that he was into dope.
也许西蒙斯就是这样找上他的
Maybe that's how Simmons got in contact with him.
于是西蒙斯雇库南杀了所有相关人员
So Simmons hires Coonan to kill them all,
包括你母亲  然后买通老朋友拉格兰
including your mother, and pays his old friend Raglan
把这起谋杀案记录为流氓犯罪
to write off their homicides as random gang violence.
这样一来  就没可能
There would've been no way to trace
把他和谋杀案联系起来
the murders back to him.
直到拉格兰决定
Until Raglan threatens to
将自己的所做作为和盘托出
reveal his role in the conspiracy,
西蒙斯就想办法杀人灭口
and Simmons has him silenced.
午饭之前保证把人逮到
We'll have him in the box before lunch.
上次看到你的时候  你还不化妆呢
You painted since the last time I was here.
你大概也就十六岁
You'd have been about 16,
跟满脸粉刺的毛头小子
wrestling some pimply kid
在他爸爸的车里嬉闹
in the back of his Daddy's wagon,
不知道要不要跟他做
wondering if you were gonna give it to him or not.
喂  该闭嘴了
Hey. That's enough.
这小子喜欢你  才敢跟我嚣张
He's sweet on you. Makes him brave.
你跟约翰·拉格兰警探什么关系
What was your association with Detective John Raglan?
拉格兰  拉格兰  拉格兰
Raglan? Raglan, Raglan, Raglan?
那个饥渴的警察  对吧
Thirsty cop, right?
没人救得了他吗
Couldn't pick a winner to save his life?
探长  如你所言
Well, Detective, our association,
我们的关系
as you put it,
几辈子以前就超越了法规的局限
exceeded the statute of limitations many moons ago.
谋杀案里不存在所谓的法规的局限
There is no statute of limitations on murder,
西蒙斯先生
Mr. Simmons.
传说中的初次交锋开始了么
And here begins what is known as the initial confrontation.
在这个审讯阶段
During this phase of the interrogation,
审讯者会侵犯
the interrogator may invade
嫌犯的个人空间
the suspect's personal space
以增加其不适感
in order to increase his discomfort.
你想侵犯我个人空间吗
You want to invade my personal space?
看着我
Look at me.
十二年前  乔安·贝克特
12 years ago, Johanna Beckett led
在华盛顿高地领导发动了
a big take back the neighborhood campaign
一场夺回生活家园的活动
in Washington Heights.
你对此肯定很不爽
And that must have pissed you off.
原来这才是主线
And this would be theme development.
借助嫌犯的视角  重现谋杀
Presenting the crime through the eyes of the suspect.
乔安·贝克特
Johanna Beckett was murdered
和她的两名同事被害
along with two of her colleagues.
凶手都是奉你命令行事的职业杀手
They were professional hits carried out on your orders.
你又让你的走狗
And you had
凶案组约翰·拉格兰警探掩盖此事
your pet homicide Detective John Raglan bury them.
看着她的脸
Look at her face.
告诉我你不记得她
Tell me you don't remember her.
知道吗  贝克特探长
You know, Detective Beckett...
我觉得我记得她
I think I do remember her.
像垃圾一样倒在小巷里流血身亡
Bled out in an alley like the trash she was.
西蒙斯先生  你最好看清楚
Mr. Simmons, you better watch it.
从上东区高地来的的有钱婊子
Rich bitch from uptown on safari in the Heights.
应该有人提醒她
Somebody should warned her
千万不要挑衅或侵犯那些牲畜们
not to feed or tease the animals.
你...
You...
要是有人提醒过  她就不会被野兽咬着
If they had, she might not have gotten eaten.
不过据我所知
From what I hear, though...
她还挺可口的
she was pretty tasty.
贝克特
whoa, Beckett!
退下  卡塞尔
Back off, Castle!
瓦肯  好好珍惜你那条老命
Remember your old life, Vulcan. Savor it.
因为我会拿了你的狗命
Because I am gonna take it all away.
退下  贝克特  别过火
Stand down. Beckett, that's enough.
退下
Stand down.
你也想来试试吗  来吧
Oh, you want some, too? Come on.
好了  好了  够了
All right, all right, that's enough!
我现在不得不放了那个混蛋
I have to kick that son of a bitch loose now.
-你意识到了吗 -长官  你也听到他说什么了
- You realize that? - Sir, you heard him.
他马上就要供认谋杀案了
He as much as confessed to the murder.
得了吧  他在耍你  你让他
Come on. He's playing you. And you let him
把你惹毛了  表现得像个该死的新人
get under your skin, acting like a damn rookie.
我们没有任何证据证明他与拉格兰或者
We've got nothing to tie him to raglan's murder
你妈妈的被害有关  你不准再调查此案了
or your mother's. You're off this case.
不  长官  你不能这么做  尤其是现在
No, sir. You can't do that. Not now.
-我已经这么做了 -不
- I just did. - No.
我已经这么做了  你现在回家去
I just did! Now you go home.
贝克特
Beckett?
-凯特 -你也一样卡塞尔  离开这里
- Kate? - You, too, Castle. Clear out.
我做错了什么
What did I do?
我不需要你在这件案子上扮演少女妙探
I don't need you playing Nancy Drew on this.
从现在起
As of this moment,
你们俩开始负责调查拉格兰的凶杀案
you two are running point on Raglan's homicide.
长官
Uh, captain, m...
我和我的搭档不想违抗命令
My partner and I don't wish to be insubordinate...
但我们想礼貌地拒绝这项任务
but we respectfully decline the assignment.
我的警徽上写的什么
What does it say on my badge?
-"长官" -现在好好读一下这精美的印刷
- "Captain." - Now read the fine print.
它的意思是赶紧行动起来去解决拉格兰的案子
It says get your ass out there and solve Raglan's murder
在我把你们俩降职为交通警察之前
before I bust you both back down to traffic.
-是 长官  -是 长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
你们想帮助她吗  找出那个枪手
You want to help her? Find that shooter.
破了这该死的案子
Solve the damn case.
如果死的是你可怎么办
What if it had been you?
我不知道你在家
I didn't know you were home.
我在新闻上听说了那起枪击
I heard about the shooting on the news.
死的有可能是你  你知道的  对吧
It could've been you. You know that, don't you?
是  但我挺好的  死的不是我
Yeah, but I'm fine. It wasn't me.
理查德  这不是你写的书
Richard, this isn't one of your books.
你不知道结局会是怎样
You don't know the ending.
昨天你只是幸运而已
You were just lucky yesterday.
你有些反应过度了  老妈  你这火从何来啊
You're overreacting, mother. Where is this coming from?
你他妈的怎么能问出这种问题
How the hell can you ask me something like that?
想一想你有多爱亚历克西斯
Think about how much you love Alexis,
再想想我有多爱你
and that is how much I love you.
你怎么敢问我的火从何而来
And don't you dare ask me where this is coming from.
你凭借着智慧和魅力以及很高的天赋
You have gotten through most of your life
顺顺利利了大半辈子
on your wit and charm and no small amount of talent.
但外面是真枪实弹的世界
But that is the real world out there,
在子弹面前施展魅力是没用的
and you can't charm your way out of a bullet.
你认为我应该全身而退吗
You think I should quit?
我认为你应该仔细想清楚
I think you should be honest with yourself
你现在这么做的动机是什么
about why you're doing this.
在没遇见她之前你写了二十二本书
You have written 22 novels before you met her,
你没有必要为了完成作品
and you didn't need to spend every day in a police station
每天都呆在警局
in order to finish them.
这早已和写书无关了
It's not about the books anymore.
你认为是西蒙斯雇的狙击手吗
So you think that Simmons hired the sniper?
如果我们找到了狙击手  我们可以问问他
If we find the sniper, we can ask him.
我觉得他一定得先把枪拆了  对吧
I figure, he had to disassemble his rifle, right?
把他的武器拆成不那么受怀疑的形状
Break his weapon down to a less conspicuous shape
才能带着它走过大厅
in order to get it through the lobby.
像一些正好能装进公文包的东西
Something that would fit inside of a briefcase.
大厅里的每个人都拿着一个该死的公文包
Everyone in that lobby's carrying a damn briefcase.
你该拿出点警探的样子来了
You should be a detective.
这件案子我们不能空手而归
We can't come up empty on this one.
我知道  老兄
I know, bro.
那是场意外事故
Whoa. That wasn't an accident.
他刚刚偷了她的门卡
He just lifted her key card.
从门卡获取狙击手信息
Well, so much for the card telling us
-这条线索就这么断了 -等一下
- who the sniper was. - Wait a minute.
他没有带手套
He's not wearing gloves.
那又怎样  他没碰到任何可印表面
So what? He didn't touch any printable surfaces.
没错  但他碰了她
Yeah, but he touched her.
我们能从尸体上找到指纹  是吧
We can print a dead body, right?
那我们为什么不能从活人身上找到呢
So why can't we print a live one?
她现在可能已经洗过澡了
She's probably showered by now.
未必  今天是周六  而且下午才刚刚过完
Not necessarily. It's Saturday. And it's barely afternoon.
来吧
Come on.
嗨  卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
嗨
Hey.
乔什去哪了
Where's Josh?
他在非洲  在拯救世界呢
Oh, he's in Africa. He's saving the world.
我给你带了一些...
Uh, I brought you some...
我只是觉得经历过这些事...
I just thought, after everything, that...
你可能需要一些...
you might wanna...
给
Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
这真的很贴心
That's really sweet.
-你想进来吗 -当然
- You wanna come in? - Sure.
房间很漂亮
Wow. Nice.
我在来的路上一直在想
You know, I was thinking on the way over here,
所有最棒的警察...《警探哈里》
all the best cops...Dirty Harry,
漫画里的哥普拉  还有 《警察学校》里面
Cobra, the guy from "Police academy"
那个会用口技模仿直升机声音的家伙
who makes the helicopter noises...
-他们都有一个共同的特点 -神勇的小跟班么
- They all have one thing common. - Plucky sidekick?
那是一方面  而且他们都是在被踢出调查组
That, and they do their very best work
之后做出了最棒的工作
after they've been booted off a case.
这就是你一路跑来这想要告诉我的吗
Is that what you came all the way over here to tell me?
蒙哥马利把我们踢出了拉格兰的案子
Montgomery booted us off the raglan murder.
但对于你妈妈的案子他只字未提
But he didn't say anything about your mother's case,
是吧
did he?
我的计划是这样的...我戴着帽子偷偷溜到警局里
Here's my plan...I sneak back into the station wearing a hat.
蒙哥马利总是每过一小时有十五分钟的
Montgomery always takes a coffee break
喝咖啡休息时间
15 minutes after the hour.
我穿着软底鞋偷偷拿走你妈妈案子的文件
I get your mother's file wearing soft shoes.
南入口处有...怎么了
The south entrance has... What?
过来卡塞尔  我给你看些东西
Come on, castle. I gotta show you something.
你知道  我有时会忘记
You know, I sometimes forget
你对这些已是刻骨铭心
that you live with this every day.
乔什知道这些吗
Josh know about this?
不知道
No.
你什么时候开始的
When did you start?
整整一夏天 当你在汉普顿的时候
Over the summer, when you were in the hamptons.
-你查到多少了 -除了我妈妈
- And how far have you gotten? - Well, aside from my mom,
被杀的还有戴安娜·卡瓦诺和詹妮弗·斯图尔特
there was also Diane Cavanaugh, Jennifer Stewart.
她们有时给我妈妈做义务劳动
They volunteered for her from time to time
为司法倡议组织
for the justice initiative.
第四位被害者是斯科特·穆雷
And then the fourth victim was Scott Murray.
他是法院里的一位文员
He was a document clerk at the courthouse.
你知道吗卡塞尔  直到今天我一直追查此案是
You know, castle, up until today, I'd always run this
建立在他们因一起正在调查的合法案件
on the theory that they got killed because of a legal case
而被谋杀的假设上
that they were working on.
我妈妈在被杀之前
My mom requested a court file
申请调查一份法庭文件
just before she was murdered,
那份文件失踪了
and that file went missing.
你妈妈肯定有私人记录
Well, your mom must have had personal papers,
日程本之类的东西可以告诉你
an appointment book, something that could tell you
她死之前在调查什么
what she was working on before she died.
我九年之前就把那些东西全看过了
Oh, I went through all of that nine years ago.
什么也没有
There's nothing.
没错  但自从那以后发生了很多事
Yeah, but a lot's happened since then.
也许你漏掉了什么
Maybe you missed something.
摸过我胳膊的那家伙是杀人犯吗
So the guy who touched my arm was a murderer?
我就知道  为什么我总是吸引变态
Figures. Why do I attract all the creeps?
我和一个叫克雷格的家伙约会过
I dated this one guy, Craig,
差不多有两个月吧  我那时感觉
for like two months, and I thought,
他就是我的唯一  有天晚上我给他打电话
like, he was the one. And I called him up one night,
他室友接的电话  告诉我
and his roommate answered the phone and told me
克雷格已经死了  我简直崩溃了
that Craig had died, and I was, like, devastated.
我和他室友  我们把他的骨灰
And me and the roommate, we scattered his ashes
撒在了中央公园
throughout central park...the whole thing.
我是靠心理引导  外加一票男人
And I worked through the stages of grief with my life coach
才挺过了悲恸期
and a lot of random guys,
正当我准备接受事实时
and I was getting into acceptance
却在一个酒吧撞到了克雷格
when I ran into Craig at a bar.
-他捏造了自己的死  -好难以置信
- He had faked his own death. - Unbelievable.
我知道  他应该做的一切只不过是告诉我他不想
I know, right? All he had to do was say he didn't want us
和我再约会下去了  我又不是什么精神变态
to date anymore. I mean, it's not like I'm some psycho.
-看上去我们找到了一枚指纹  -谢谢
- Looks like we got a lift. - Thank you.
我睡觉晚也是挺好一件事吧
Oh. Well, good thing I slept in late, huh?
她的日程本里面没有任何线索
There's nothing in her appointment book.
至少没有什么是我能看出苗头的
Not that I can make sense of anyway.
她有她自己的记录方式
She had her own system.
我爸和我从来没看懂过
I mean, my dad and I could never figure it out.
你那时真可爱
Aww. You were adorable.
这是你妈妈拍的吗
Did your mom take these?
是的  大概在她死前三周
Yeah, about three weeks before she died.
啊  我好想看你现场摆造型啊
Oh, I don't get to see you in action?
信我吧  卡塞尔  一点都没看头
Trust me, Castle. It was not pretty.
那就更得看看了
Oh, now I have to see it.
怎么了
What?
这一卷有24张底片
There's 24 exposures on this role,
却只有20张照片
but there's only 20 pictures.
这是什么
What is it?
无人的街道
An empty street?
卡塞尔  这是我妈妈被杀的地点
Castle, this is where my mom was murdered.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这些照片是她被害
I mean, these pictures were developed
一周前拍的
a week before she was killed.
她干嘛要拍那条巷子的照片呢
Why would she be taking photos of that alley?
我不知道  我一直以为
I don't know. I always thought
这只是方便凶手作案的地方
it was just a convenient place for the killer to attack.
因为那里又黑暗  又隐秘
I mean, it was dark, it was secluded.
如果还有其他原因呢
What if there was more to it than that?
如果在她被害时
What if she was looking into something
她在那里寻找什么呢
that happened in that alley when they killed her?
我得查查以前的档案和报告
Well, I'd have to go into the old archives and reports,
但蒙哥马利队长现在
and captain Montgomery won't
是不会让我回警局的
let me back into the precinct right now.
我去
I'll go.
哈尔·洛克伍德
Hal Lockwood.
男性  白人  32岁
Male, white, 32.
身家清白
Record's clean.
根据记录
According to this,
洛克伍德连交通罚单都没领过
Lockwood's never had so much as a traffic citation.
信用记录仅可以查到两年前
Credit history only goes back about two years.
肯定是用假身份证
Well, it's gotta be a cover I.D.
他的信用卡有在使用
huh. His credit card's active.
上面显示洛克伍德现在入住了
It shows Lockwood's checked into a corporate suite
市中心的商用套房
in midtown right now.
纽约警局  走走走
NYPD! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
纽约警局  没人
NYPD clear!
没人
Clear.
看来我们刚好错过了
Looks like we just missed him.
看这个
Yo. Look at this.
他一直在跟踪她
He's been watching her.
莱恩和埃斯波西托追查到
Ryan and Esposito traced your sniper
狙击手在市中心的一个商用套房里
to a corporate suite in midtown.
自拉格兰谋杀案以来  他一直盯着你
He's been on you since Raglan's murder.
这不只是持枪的疯子
This isn't just a kook with a deer rifle
还是现实版的《麦田里的守望者》
and a copy of "Catcher in the rye."
这家伙是职业杀手  专业训练且资金充足
This guy is a professional-- highly trained and well-funded.
也许是某团伙中的一员
Maybe part of a team.
长官  我们得通知卡塞尔
Sir, we gotta let Castle know.
他知道了  他回了12分局
He does. He's back at the 12th.
我在男厕所抓到他
I caught him in the men's room,
正在偷看旧报告
poking through some old reports.
这事你有什么解释的吗
You want to tell me about that?
你真的想知道吗
You real want to know?
我会把细节告诉你
Listen, I'm gonna have to put a detail on you.
但你必须呆在家里
But I need you to stay home.
如果这狙击手是冲着我来的
If this sniper is after me,
最安全的地方就是警局
the safest place in the city is the 12th.
你得让我跟这个案子  罗伊
You gotta let me have this, Roy.
让我回来查我妈妈的案子
Let me come back and work on my mom's case.
不  我很抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
鉴证组分析了
C.S.U. Analyzed the capsules
在洛克伍德套房里找到的胶囊
we found in Lockwood's suite
发现含有一种高浓缩
and found they contain a highly concentrated form
叫普拉西泮的抗抑郁药
of an antianxiety drug called prazepam.
这就对了
That fits.
优秀的狙击手得克服心跳的影响
A good sniper fires between heartbeats.
在特种部队里  有些人
Back in special forces, some of the guys
会使用抗抑郁药使心跳放慢
would use antianxiety meds to slow down their heart rate.
给他们更多射击的时间
gives 'em more time to shoot.
但这些不是从普通商贩那里就能买到的
But these didn't come from any commercial lab.
而是来源于大街上贩毒分子
They were hand-ground by someone on the street,
非常精通药理的人
someone very good with chemicals.
比如瓦肯·西蒙斯
Someone like Vulcan Simmons.
我也认为是这样  但是看看这个
I thought the same thing, but check this out.
毒贩有时会用这样的标签
Dealers sometimes use symbols like these
来标识产品
to mark their product.
这些不是西蒙斯的标签
These symbols don't belong to Simmons.
这是苏活区一个名叫查德·罗迪克的
They're the brand of a street pharmacist
江湖药剂师的品牌
in soho named Chad Rodrick.
查德·罗迪克
Chad Rodrick.
你运气一定很好吧
You must be one lucky guy.
你曾因持有假麻黄碱
You've been arrested for possession of pseudoephedrine,
伪造3份处方
possession of forged triplicate prescriptions,
以及制造管制药物的罪名被逮捕
and the manufacture of a controlled substance,
但从未被定罪
but never convicted.
那些都是误会
Those are all misunderstandings.
我只是一名普通大学生
I'm just a college student
只不过把我爸的律师号码放在了快捷拨号里
with my father's lawyer on speed dial.
知道自己为何在这里吗
You know why you're here?
不知道  但我想应该
No, but I'm going to guess it
和班级结怨有关
has something to do with class resentment.
就凭你们这种级别能插手这案子
I bet it's a special treat
一定是得到了什么特殊待遇吧
for you to interrogate above your station.
你来这里是因为你贩卖这些
You're here because you sold these...
给他
to him.
但我们不是缉毒警察  查德
but we're not dope cops, Chad.
这些  我们没兴趣
So these-- we don't care about.
他  才是我们想要的
Him... We want.
恐怕帮不上忙  你们不能逮捕我
I'm afraid I can't help you. You guys can't arrest me.
你们没有证据
You don't have proof of anything.
我们不会逮捕你的
Oh... We're not gonna arrest you, Chad.
我们只会拘留你一会儿
We're just gonna detain you for a while...
在看守所里
In lockup.
没错  我们关了个假释犯
yeah, we've got a parolee in there.
强奸犯
Sex offender--
1米83  有钱有门路
6'1", couple bills and change.
人称薄荷糖
They call him peppermint.
他会很喜欢
And he'd just love to meet
你这种级别的年轻帅哥
a handsome young man of your station.
我们知道你贩卖普拉西泮
We know you sold custom-blend prazepam,
这种管制药物
which is a controlled substance,
但  我们今天给你特殊优待
But... We're running a special today.
我们就想知道在哪能找到他
All we want to know is where we can find him.
或者
Or...
你可以呆在看守所  会会你的新朋友
You can go to lockup... And meet your new friend.
听着
Listen...
我两个星期前卖的  但不是给他
I sold those two weeks ago, but not to him.
我从来没见过这个人
I've never seen this guy before in my life.
-谁买的  -卓琳  我的一位常客
- Who bought the pills?  - Jolene. She's one of my regulars.
-形容一下  -金发  30多岁
- Tell me about her.  - Blonde, 30s.
-我想她住在布鲁克林附近  -姓什么
- I think she lives somewhere in Brooklyn.  - Last name?
我不知道
I don't know.
她要买东西的时候才出现
She just shows up when she wants something.
我发誓  我甚至都不知道怎么联系她
I swear. I don't even know how to get ahold of her.
你跟蒙哥马利谈过了
You talked to Montgomery?
是的
Yeah.
卡塞尔  我想你做些事
Castle, there's something I need you to do.
说说看
Name it.
回家
Go home.
想都别想  既入此门  再无畏惧
Forget it. Fear does not exist in this dojo.
我戴上警徽的那一刻起便不计生死了
Look, I signed up for this when I put that badge on.
但你没有  这不是你的斗争
You didn't. It's not your fight.
扯淡
The hell it isn't.
我整天围着你转并不是存心烦你
I don't hang around you just to annoy you.
我屡屡半夜赶到犯罪现场
I don't ride out to murder scenes
并非是为了满足我的好奇心
in the middle of the night to satisfy some morbid curiosity.
如果仅仅为了那些  我老早就离开了
If that's all this was, I would've quit a long time ago.
那你为何一直往返在我身边  里克
Well, then why do you keep coming back, Rick?
听着  我也许没有警徽
Look, I may not have a badge,
除非你把阿丽克西斯为我生日
unless you count the chocolate one
做的巧克力警徽算上
that Alexis gave me for my birthday,
但我要告诉你
But I'll tell you this--
不管你喜不喜欢  我就是你神勇的小跟班
Like it or not, I'm your plucky sidekick.
神勇的小跟班总是被杀的那个
Plucky sidekick always gets killed.
那么就做搭档吧
Your partner, then.
好吧  你发现了什么
Okay. What'd you find?
你记得拉格兰在咖啡室说过
You remember what Raglan said back at the coffee shop
-这事要回溯到19年前吗  -嗯
- about this thing going back 19 years? - Uh-huh.
原来  在你母亲遇害前
Turns out, before your mother,
那巷子发生过另一宗谋杀案
there was another murder in this alley,
当时那里曾是叫做巴勒莫之子的
back when it was the back entrance to a club
俱乐部后门  那是黑帮聚集地
Called sons of palermo. It was a mafia hangout.
我不知道那曾是个俱乐部
I didn't know this was a club.
那在你母亲遇害一年前停业了
Well, it got shut down years before your mother was killed,
就在一个叫鲍勃·阿门的联调局探员
After an FBI agent by the name of Bob Armen
-被杀害后  -上面说阿门
- Was killed in the alley behind it. - It says Armen
当时正在黑帮当卧底
was working undercover in the mafia.
不知怎么的他们盯上了阿门
Somehow the mob got on to Armen,
-用了传统方法  -就地正法
- used the old family remedy. - Summary execution.
纽约警局调查阿门谋杀案时
The NYPD arrested a mob
逮捕了一个叫乔·布伽地的黑帮成员
in Armen's murder--a guy by the name of Joe Pulgatti.
他后来认罪了
He later pled guilty.
猜猜是哪个警官逮捕他的
And guess who the arresting officer was.
约翰·拉格兰警官
Officer John Raglan.
你母亲是民权辩护律师
Your mother was a civil rights attorney.
她有说过阿门的谋杀案吗
Did she ever mention Armen's murder
-或是布伽地认罪的事情  -没有
- or Pulgatti's conviction? - No,
但两者肯定是有关联的
but there's gotta be a connection somewhere.
我打赌布伽地能帮我们弄清楚
I bet Pulgatti could shed some light on it.
我没杀害鲍比·阿门
I didn't kill Bobby Armen.
那你为什么要认罪
Then why'd you plead guilty?
因为我不喜欢刑讯逼供的滋味
'cause I don't like needles.
拉格兰警探声称命案发生时
Detective Raglan places you in the alley
你在巷子里
at the time of the murder.
没错  我当时跟鲍比在巷子
Yeah, I was in that alley with Bobby.
我是那起谋杀案的唯一目击者
I was the only witness to his murder,
但那不是故意行凶
but it wasn't a hit.
那次是绑架失控了
It was a kidnapping that went sideways.
三个戴着滑雪面具的男人从货车出来
Three guys in ski masks rolled up in a van,
说他们要带我在城里一日游
said they wanted to take me on a tour of the city.
鲍比试着制止他们  他去夺其中一人的枪
Bobby tried to stop 'em, he went for one of their guns
最后落得如此下场
and wound up on the wrong end of it.
那些家伙是敌对帮派的吗
Were the guys from a rival family?
不  不可能  我们当时正在停战
No. No way. We had a truce going back then
因为那时候
bwecause there was this, uh,
出现了一个神秘帮派  都是职业绑架犯
ghost crew out there-- professional kidnappers
以五大帮派的成员为目标
targeting members of all five families.
我当时跟鲍比在巷子里
Look, I was in that alley with Bobby.
但没人会知道的
But no one else could've known that.
那巷子是个盲区
It was a blind alley.
鲍比遇害时  除了我就只剩下
And the only other people in it when Bobby was shot
那些开枪的人了
were the people who shot him.
现在  你说说看  探长
So you tell me, detective...
拉格兰怎么会知道我在那里呢
how could Raglan have known I was there?
你是说  拉格兰是其中一个绑架犯
You're saying Raglan was one of the kidnappers?
那时候
There was, uh...
有个叫乔安·贝克特的律师
A lawyer named Johanna Beckett.
你认识她吗
Are you familiar with her?
大概在你入狱七年后
She was murdered in the alley
她在那个巷子遇害了
about seven years into your incarceration.
你跟她长得很像  知道吗
You look just like her, you know?
你一走进来的时候
You first walked in here...
我还以为见到了亡灵
It was like I was looking at a ghost.
从她形容你的样子
The way she talked about you,
我早该猜到你后来会成为警察
I should've known you'd become a cop.
我  我给所有
I-I-I sent letters...
能找到的律师寄过信
to every lawyer I could find.
你母亲是唯一
And your mother was the only one
回信的人
who wrote me back,
唯一愿意在我身上冒险的人
the only one willing to take a chance on me.
她不在乎我是个混混
She didn't care that I was a thug.
她只在乎事实
All she cared about was the truth.
她来探访我
She came to visit me here
并且说她会负责跟进我的案子
and she said she'd look into my case.
不久后  我发现她被杀害了
Later, I found out she was murdered.
别为了追查这件案子丢了性命
Don't get yourself killed chasing this thing.
相信我的话  没有比揣着警徽的杀手
Take it from me. There's nothing more dangerous out there
更危险的了
than a killer with a badge.
我们晚点再讨论直接命令是什么意思
We'll talk about the definition of a direct order later.
现在  我只想知道你发现了什么
Right now, I just want to hear what you found.
好的  到目前为止我们知道
Okay, so here's what we know so far--
十九年前  拉格兰和至少两位警察
19 years ago, Raglan and at least 2 other cops
为了赎金而绑架黑帮成员
were kidnapping mobsters for ransom.
当他们试着抓走
Things went south when they
乔·布伽地的时候场面失去控制
tried to snatch Joe Pulgatti.
他们误杀了卧底探员
They mistakenly killed an undercover fed
-鲍勃·阿门  -为了自保
- named Bob Armen.  - To cover their asses,
他们将阿门的谋杀案嫁祸给布伽地
They pinned Armen's murder on Pulgatti.
而七年后
And then seven years later,
我母亲和她的同事们
my mom and a group of her colleagues
为了帮布伽地上诉而追查真相
tried to put together an appeal for Pulgatti.
那些警察们知道如果案子被翻审
Now the cops knew that if the case got overturned,
他们的勾当就会曝光
They would all be exposed.
于是他们雇迪克·库南杀了所有人
So they hired Dick Coonan to kill all of them.
而拉格兰将他们的杀人案
And Raglan wrote off their homicides
归于随机的暴力案件
as random gang violence.
还不止这些
And that would've been the end of it,
拉格兰发现自己将要死了
But Raglan found out he was dying,
决定坦白招供
decided he wanted to come clean.
所以他们必须将他灭口
So they had to silence him, too.
布伽地说货车上有三个绑架犯
Pulgatti said that there were three kidnappers in that van.
表示至少还有两个在逍遥法外
That means there's at least two conspirators out there now.
而我们知道了其中一个是
And we already know who one of 'em is--
拉格兰的老同学  盖瑞·麦卡利斯特
Raglan's old academy buddy, Gary Mccallister.
你怎么知道的
How you know that?
我找到了当时的警力调度记录
I pulled the dispatcher's log from the archives.
拉格兰逮捕布伽地时
There was another unit backing Raglan
还有有另一个警员在场
when he arrested Pulgatti--
那就是机动巡逻警员盖瑞·麦卡利斯特
A one-man patrol unit-- officer Gary Mccallister.
捉住那个畜牲
Get that son of a bitch.
瓦肯·西蒙斯跟这事没有任何关系
Vulcan Simmons had nothing to do with this.
但身为退休警员  你知道他是完美的嫌犯
But as a former cop, you knew that he fit the part,
于是你利用他摆脱我们
And so you used him throw us off
但事实上你跟拉格兰
when the truth is that you and Raglan
都参与了谋杀和绑架
were up to your necks in murder and kidnappings.
听着  你现在推断起来好像很容易
Listen, it's easy for you to sit in judgment now,
但你不在现场
but you weren't there.
我们做了我们应该做的事
We did what we thought we had to do.
而且你们做了可不少
And you did plenty.
绑架  掩盖真相
Kidnapping, cover-ups.
你杀了联邦警员  然后嫁祸给布伽地
You killed a fed, and then you pinned it on Pulgatti.
让我告诉你乔·布伽地的为人
You want me to tell you about Joe Pulgatti,
多少人因为他被送进医院
About the people he put in the hospital,
还有那些被他丢下河的人
The ones he put in the river?
他和他的手下
He and the rest of those jackals
在城市里胡作非为几十年
fed on this city for decades,
但你不能制裁他们
But you couldn't touch them
因为他们买通了所有人
because they bought everybody.
还有  我想让你知道的
And this part--this part I want you to know,
因为我对这不感到惭愧
'cause this part I'm not ashamed of,
因为至少我们有尝试过
'cause at least we tried to do something.
这不光彩也不合法  但这是正确的
It wasn't pretty and it wasn't legal, but it was right.
为了赎金而绑架别人是正确的吗
Kidnapping people for ransom was right?
我们叫这拘留
We called it incarceration.
没错  我们从街上抓走他们
Yeah, we grabbed 'em off the street,
带去某个地方然后好好调教一下
and we'd take them somewhere and we'd tune them up.
我们让他们吓得屁滚尿流  至少有好一会儿
We put the fear of god into 'em, at least for a while.
但我们知道不能永远关着他们
But we knew we couldn't hold 'em forever.
所以我们设了保释金
So we set bail.
而且我告诉你  赎金相当高
And I'm here to tell you that we set it high.
如果那些混蛋想回到街上
If those bastards wanted back on the street,
他们必须有所付出
they were gonna have to pay for their way.
当我母亲为布伽地的上诉做调查时
When my mom put together that appeal for Pulgatti,
你担心她会找上你
you got worried that she'd get on to you,
-所以你雇了迪克·库南去杀害她  -不
- and so you hired Dick Coonan to kill her. - No.
然后当拉格兰良心发现
And then when Raglan grew a conscience,
-你也把他杀了  -不
- You had him killed, too. - No.
我跟那事没有关系
I didn't have anything to do with that.
那个  那是其他人干的
That was... That was somebody else.
-谁  -你永远也碰不到他
- Who? - Somebody you'll never touch.
是谁
Who?
你不明白  探长
You don't understand, detective.
你把恶魔唤醒了
You woke the dragon.
这事比你想象中要严重得多
And this is so much bigger than you realize.
我说完了
And I'm done talking.
我要请律师
I want a lawyer.
他害怕某人  而那人不是警察
He's afraid of someone, and it's not a cop.
我们要找到那个枪手
We gotta find that shooter.
我想我们找到线索了
I think we got a lead on him.
据罗迪克所说
According to Rodrick,
我们在洛克伍德的商务套房里
a woman named Jolene
找到的那些药片  是一个
bought those capsules that we found
-叫卓琳的女人从他那买的  -女朋友吗
- in Lockwood's corporate suite.  - Girlfriend?
可能吧  我们只知道她是个金发女郎
Probably. All we got is blonde,
三十多岁  住在布鲁克林
30s, lives in Brooklyn.
所以我们把她的特征
So we fed her descriptors
输到车管所的数据库里进行查找
into the DMV database.
查找结果缩小到了两个女人
Got it narrowed down to two women --
卓琳·格兰杰和卓琳·安德斯
Jolene Granger and Jolene Anders.
你们俩去找卓琳·安德斯
Okay, you guys take Jolene Anders.
我们去找格兰杰  找到她以后打电话给我
We'll take Granger. You call me when you get her.
遵命
Roger that.
卓琳·格兰杰  我们是纽约警局的
Jolene Granger, NYPD.
卓琳
Jolene?
我是埃斯波西托
Esposito.
卓琳·格兰杰死了
Jolene Granger is dead.
我们这就过去  走吧
We're on our way. Let's go.
捂上耳朵
Cover your ears!
埃斯波西托  埃斯波西托
Esposito? Esposito?!
你查到什么了
So what do you got?
你所听到的是闪光弹的声音
What you heard was a flash bang.
他俩肯定在洛克伍德手上
Lockwood must've grabbed 'em.
我们目前找到的唯一东西就是他们的手机
Only thing we've recovered so far are their cell phones.
他怕我们用全球定位系统追踪他们的位置
He dumped both of their phones,
于是把他们俩的手机都丢了
so we can't GPS track 'em.
我们也找不到卓琳的手机
We couldn't find Jolene's cell phone either.
肯定也被洛克伍德给扔了
Lockwood must have gotten rid of it.
因为我们可以通过她的手机找到他
Because her phone was a link to him.
她用手机给他打过电话
She called him on it.
她家里肯定会有手机账单
There's gotta be a cell phone bill around here somewhere.
我要恭喜你们两个
I want to congratulate you both.
我不知道你们是怎么找到我家的
I don't know how you found my place,
但是我做这行也做了很久了
but I've been doing this kind of work for a while now,
从来没人如此接近过我
and no one's ever come that close to me.
现在的问题就是  你们的调查
My problem is that your investigation
比我预期的要深入
has gone further than I expected.
为了能够完成我的任务
And now in order for me to finish my job,
我需要知道你们对我和我的雇主
I need to know exactly what you know about me
到底有多少了解
and my employer.
我很尊重你们两个
Now I got a lot of respect for you guys.
干嘛  我是说真的
What? I do.
所以我要跟你们做个交易
Now I'm gonna make you a deal.
你们把我想知道的事情告诉我
You tell me what I need to know,
咱们来个专业人士间的对话
one pro to another,
那么我就给你们脑袋来一枪
and I will put
让你们死得痛快点
bullet in your brain.
要是你们不说
You don't,
或是你们敢耍我
you jerk me around,
那今夜对你们来说将是漫漫长夜
and you will be begging me to before this night is up.
我选后者
I'm gonna have to go with option "B".
说的对
Oh, yeah.
我们绝对会好好耍耍你
We're definitely gonna jerk you around.
她的账号是多少
What's her account number?
5892-639-1199
5892-639-1199.
好了  如果我们能查出她母亲的娘家姓
All right. If we can figure out her mother's maiden name,
他们就会把密码通过电邮发给我们
they'll e-mail us the password.
你们去好好查一下卓琳·格兰杰的资料
I need everything you can get on Jolene Granger,
特别是她母亲的娘家姓
specifically her mother's maiden name.
给爷爷听好了  龟孙子
Listen, ass clown,
我在教会学校待了十二年
I was in catholic school for 12 years.
我以前上课讲话  他们就这样罚我
Hell. They used to do this to me for talking in cla --
你死定了  洛克伍德
You're dead, Lockwood.
开始的时候  每个人都会虚张声势
You know, they always start off with bravado.
待会有你们求饶的时候  这池子里是冰水
The begging comes later. See, this is ice cold water.
冰水进到他肺里的时候会产生剧烈的灼烧感
It'll burn like hell when it hits his lungs,
但是他不会马上失去知觉
but he won't lose consciousness right away.
但是只要你告诉我  警察查到了什么
But all this stops when you tell me
我就会放过他
how much the cops know!
她打的最后几个电话里
Lockwood would've been one of the
肯定有一个是洛克伍德的号码
last numbers she called.
找到了
Uh, got it.
917-555-0176
Uh, 917-555-0176
-追踪一下这个号码  -卡塞尔  你又破案了
- I need a GPS track.  - Castle, you've done it again.
这家伙肯定大老远地就能看到特警队
That guy is gonna spot a SWAT team
然后通知洛克伍德
from a block away, warn Lockwood.
我们要是动用装甲部队的话  他俩就死定了
We call in the cavalry, and they're both dead.
我黔驴技穷了
I'm open to dumb ideas here.
正好  我有个主意
Good. 'Cause I got one.
他不信  卡塞尔
He's not buying it, Castle.
感觉棒极了
That was amazing.
我是说  你刚刚打他那下
The -- the way you knocked him out, I mean.
那真是
It was...
我们走
Let's go.
好吧
Okay!
别跟这混蛋说一个字
Ohh. Don't tell this jack hole anything.
对不起  兄弟  我看不下去了
I'm sorry, bro. I can't watch this.
听我说  你太迟了
Listen to me. You're too late.
警察已经知道我干了你妈
The cops already know all about me and your mom.
打碎他一个膝盖
Shoot out one of his kneecaps.
不
No!
不  不
No! No!
-不  不  -住手
- No! No!  - Come on! Hey!
你还好吧
You okay?
从来没这么好过
Never better.
你好呀  查克·诺里斯[空手道世界冠军  动作片演员]
Hey there, Chuck Norris.
你的手怎么样
How's the hand?
疼得要死
Uh, excruciating.
莱恩和埃斯波西托怎么样了
How's Ryan and Esposito?
体温有些过低  自尊心受损
Mm, mild hypothermia...wounded pride.
猜猜看哪个会先好起来
Guess which one will heal first.
谢谢你
Thank you...
刚才做我的后援
for having my back in there.
随时效劳
Always.
我们把你登记为无名氏
We booked you as John Doe.
你真名绝对不是哈尔·洛克伍德
You sure as hell aren't Hal Lockwood.
是谁雇的你
Who hired you?
我曾将很多人送进这里
I put a lot of people in this place.
其中一些人想要杀我
Some of them want to kill me.
而其他人  这辈子从未受过这么公正的待遇
Others, never been treated so fairly in their lives.
所以他们对我产生了一种感情
So they form this attachment to me.
把我看做了他们最喜爱的老师
It's like I'm their favorite schoolteacher.
你在这所监狱的这段时间里
Some of those people might visit you
他们其中的一些人可能会探望一下你
while you're in here...
就像是缠着史顾己的那些鬼魂一样
like the ghosts that visit Scrooge.
跟他们相处一段时间以后
And after some time with them,
你也许会发现  自己变成了一个崭新的人
you might find yourself a changed man.
所以我会每个礼拜
So I will be back here
都到这来
week after week
问你到底是谁雇了你
to ask you who hired you...
直到奇迹发生的那天
until that miracle occurs.